

### Web • C# • Developer

connelhooley.uk • me@connelhooley.uk • LinkedIn

## **Background**

I am a 27-year-old software engineer based in Norwich. My preferred language is **C#** although I also have experience with **TypeScript** and **PHP**.

I have also recently started to take a keen interest in **F#** and functional paradigms. I have written an in-depth article introducing C# developers to F# that you can find <a href="here">here</a>. I also have experience with the Actor model via **Akka.NET**. My love for TDD and the Actor model lead me to write an Akka.NET unit test framework that you can find <a href="here">here</a>.

My hobbies include playing football and table tennis. I am a Newcastle United fan.

# **Experience**

### **Applications Developer** Modality Systems

Feb 2015 - Present

During this role I have worked on various enterprise software solutions. In the past year or so Modality has made a lot of changes to become a more truly agile dev team. This has involved building out build & release pipelines in VSTS and embracing TDD & testing automation. This involved a large mentality shift with regards to how QA is approached. We now try and involve our testers as early as possible with each user story. I have particularly enjoyed embracing TDD.

During my time at Modality I have worked on various projects. I lead the design of one project that tested a customer's network by making test Skype calls. This was a very interesting project that involved the co-ordination of 50+ machines. It used <a href="Akka.NET">Akka.NET</a> and <a href="SignalR">SignalR</a> to achieve the distributed computing required. The machines could be configured using an <a href="Angular2">Angular2</a> TypeScript web application. Durings this project we hired a junior dev who was brought into the project. I mentored him as he had not done much TDD before and it was an extremely rewarding experience. I was also stand-in scrum master for this project.

I have also been involved in various Microsoft TAP programs which were a great experience. I have found working with the other developers at Modality Systems extremely rewarding.

#### **Applications Developer** C A Design Services

*Jan 2014 – Jan 2015* 

This was my first development role. Upon starting the role I initially performed small support tasks and developed an in house web site to aid support for a particular product. During this time, I also wrote software using Microsoft ASP.NET and C# for the first time since college. I then moved on to developing enhancements and bug fixes to older existing developments. These systems were usually 3-tier ASP.NET Web Form Applications with T-SQL databases.

As my role in the department grew I eventually began working on new developments and was the first person at the company to code a website using an ORM back end (Entity Framework) and the MVC design pattern (ASP.NET MVC). My first project was for the large retail firm Sainsbury's. To

{C.H}
Connel Hooley

### Web • C# • Developer

connelhooley.uk • me@connelhooley.uk • LinkedIn

deliver software to such a large firm in my first ever greenfield project, on my own, using new technologies, is something I am very proud of. I also began writing unit tests for the first time during my time at C A Design Services.

Despite almost all of my knowledge gained at C A Design Services being self-taught, I feel I have a learned a lot during my time there. This includes MVC, ORMs, C#, Dependency Injection and TDD. Since I had only made Java web applications at university, the fact that I made the shift to C#/.NET gave me the confidence that I could learn and adapt to any language or framework when given the correct amount of time.

# **Notable Projects**

#### **Test Node V1**

Aug 2015 - Sept 2015

This tool was a console application that read in an XML file and then placed and answered Skype for Business calls. It makes heavy use of the async .NET code to perform tasks concurrently. Although originally designed to be a tool to help consultants diagnose issues, an entire offering was eventually built around it. Consultants would deploy several instances of the software and leave them calling each other. They would then go back and analyse the call quality data that the nodes had generated.

#### **Test Node V2**

December 2016 - May 2017

Due to the popularity of the first version of the Test Node software, we needed to create a version of the software that configured itself and was extremely fault tolerant. Instead of configuring each Node individually, a centralised web server that tells each node which other node to perform a Skype for Business call to. The centralised web server ensures each node calls every other node in a round-robin schedule, whilst ensuring no nodes receive two calls at the same time. It was configured using a web portal. The project used technologies such as C#, Akka.NET, SignalR and Angular2.

### Sainsbury's Store Space®

*Mar 2014 – Sept 2014* 

My responsibility in this project was to create a web application that interacted with data sent up to a server through an AutoCAD extension developed by a colleague. The website offered data viewing, reporting, panoramic photos, file storage and user management. It used technologies such as C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, Ninject and jQuery.



# Web • C# • Developer

<u>connelhooley.uk</u> • <u>me@connelhooley.uk</u> • <u>LinkedIn</u>

# Qualifications

BSc Hons in Software Engineering	University of East Anglia 2010 – 2013
2:2	
BTEC National Diploma in ICT	Great Yarmouth College 2008 – 2010
Triple distinction	
GCSEs	Cliff Park High School 2002 – 2006

Grade A: English Language Grade B: English Literature

Grade C: Science × 2, Maths, Statistics, ICT, Electronics, Art, PE, RE